Jon Olsson

UX Designer

Details

Address

Trangården 1 Löddeköpinge, 24630 Sweden

Phone

+46724517178

Email

aadrianswe@gmail.com

Links

Portfolio

Linkedin

Skills

UX Design Process

• • • •

Adobe XD

• • • •

Prototyping

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Information Architecture

.

Ideation

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Usability testing

• • • •

Competitive Research

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

MIRO

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Figma

• • • • •

HTML & CSS

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Profile

I enjoy a versatile role with creative elements. As a person, I am **sociable** and **positive** and love to share this energy with colleagues and customers. I am especially passionate about designing and testing. What **drives me** is the feeling of living up to someone's expectations and delivering something I can feel proud of.

Internships

UX Designer, Adesso

I returned to Purple Scout (Now Adesso) for my second internship. I was assigned to work on a multitude of projects and oversaw the whole UX design process.

Tasks included ideation, competitive research, user personas, scenarios, prototyping, task flows, mood boards, icon design, evaluation and usability testing.

UX Designer, Purple Scout

I did my first internship as part of my studies at a Copenhagen-based consultancy. I worked on a multitude of projects, designing the UX as well as UI experience.

Tasks included competitive research, user personas, scenarios, prototyping, task flows, mood boards and usability testing.

Education

EC Utbildning, UX Designer

- Businessmanship & Communication. 15hp
- UX production. 15hp
- UX design. 20hp
- UX process. 105hp.
- Interface design. 20hp.
- Information architecture. 25hp.
- Frontend programming 35hp
- Project/Agile methods 20hp
- Prototyping 25p
- Dissertation, 35hp.

Languages

Swedish

• • • •

English

• • • • •

Spanish; Castilian

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Danish

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

EC Utbildning, Java Developer

- Programming in java. 20hp
- Advanced UML object orientation. 25hp
- Data structures and algorithms. 20hp
- Network programming with Java. 20hp.
- Database handling. 25hp.
- Web application development. 25hp.
- Java mobile app development. 25hp.
- Dissertation. 40hp.

Employment History

UX Designer, Swedcon18

Aug 2022

Malmö

Freelance role. I am presently working with other designers to create a new prototype for the healthcare cross-platform application *CARELYO*, intended for the African continent. The existing design is being revamped with focus on *design principles* and *accessibility*. We work in cross-functional agile teams.

Tasks included ideation, competitive research, prototyping, task flows and icon design.

System Developer, Data Ductus

Aug 2019 - Mar 2020

Malmö

In-house consultant. Java, HTML, CSS and C#.

Reason for leaving

Lack of assignments. Left company to begin studies.

Integration Specialist, Pulsen

Oct 2017 - May 2019

Gothenburg

In-house consultant. Daily customer interaction. XML, Java, SQL and MEL.

Reason for leaving

Relocated to Malmö.

Moderator and Translator, letgo

Nov 2015 — Oct 2017

Barcelona

Student job. Moderation, translation and customer support.

Reason for leaving

I graduated and started working as a developer.

Account Manager, OFX

Jun 2013 − Sep 2015 City of London

FX trade, market analysis and advice, enhanced due diligence and anti-money laundering.

Reason for leaving

Left London to begin studies.

Account Manager, Caxton FX

FX trade, market analysis and advice, enhanced due diligence and anti-money laundering.

Reason for leaving

Redundancy, expansion plans canceled.

Customer Support Agent, Mr Green

Customer support, staff training, due diligence and payment processing.

Reason for leaving

Company relocated to Malta.

Claims Assessor, Air France

Customer support, payment processing, relationship management and dispute resolution.

Reason for leaving

Temporary contract. Company could not offer full time position.

References

References available upon request